SAURABH SANJAY FASATE

Capgemini | M. Tech, IIT Kanpur

@ saurabhphasate@gmail.com

J 88888 05670

GitHub

LinkedIn



EXPERIENCE

Software Developer

Capgemini

Aug 2022 - present

Bangalore Karnataka

• Drift Communication Service

- Successfully led the design and development of enterprise-level microservices for a merger of two giant Telecom Groups, serving 11 million customers in Europe using AWS, Java, Spring Boot, PL/SQL, and Linux.
- Created detailed Low-Level Design documents covering system requirements and fault tolerance strategies; improved system reliability by 25% and minimized error rates, ensuring robust performance and scalability.
- Build a web application using 3-tier architecture for real-time outage notifications to consumers via email and SMS.
- Created a microservice for **nightly ETL**, transferring data from Azure Databricks to Oracle servers to fetch customer data using AOuth.
- Enhanced and optimized web application performance by 20% through effective implementation of indexing in PL/SQL
- Conducted code reviews, and performed load, stress, unit, integration, and E2E testing.

Broker Application:

- Integrated multiple third-party network provider systems with an error-registering ticketing system to log network issues from customers and outages from providers.
- Developed backend REST APIs with POST, PATCH, and GET requests for creating, updating, and retrieving trouble ticket information.
- Designed and implemented cron jobs to fetch customer details and complaints, automating the transfer to the respective network providers.

• Munity Social Media REST App:

- Developed and deployed a social media REST API: "Munity" (GITHUB Link)
- Competency: Core Java, Java 8, Spring boot, Hibernate, PostgreSQL, Maven, Git, Docker, Kubernetes, Google Cloud Platform

• Google Cloud Asset Development:

- Developed and deployed an asset for GCP using python scripting on Google Cloud Platform
- Competency: Python scripting, MySQL database, Google Cloud Platform

Subject Matter Expert CHEGG

Mar 2020 - Aug 2020

Remote, India

 Provided detailed and accurate solutions to academic questions across various subjects, ensuring high-quality educational support for students

PROJECT HIGHLIGHTS

Portfolio hosting using GITHUB

- Developed and hosted a profile page on a web-browser using a free hosting feature of Github
- Made use of "Github Action" CI/CD tool for continuous updation of the Profile page

Sorting Algorithm Visualization (GITHUB Link)

- Developed a Java Application which will visualize the sorting algorithms.
- Implemented a few sorting algorithms like Bubble sort, Quick sort.

SUMMARY

Back-end developer with a master's degree and 2+ years of experience in designing, developing and implementing Enterprise level Web Applications, API's, third-party integration, databases, Strong problem-solving skills and ability to contribute to all phases of software development life cycle. Seeking opportunities to utilize my technical expertise and collaborate with a dynamic team

SKILLS

Back End Java 8, Python, C++
Front End HTML, CSS, JavaScript
DBMS Oracle PL/SQL, Indexing

OS Linux, Windows

DevOps Docker, Kubernetes, AWS, GCPMisc. Springboot, Hibernate, Git, Maven, Postman, GitHub, OAuth, DSA, OOPs

EDUCATION

Year	Deg/Class	Institute	CPI/%
2020-22	M.Tech	IIT Kanpur	9.37/10
	Structures		
2015-19	B.Tech (Civil)	COEP,Pune	7.28/10
2015	Class XII	HSC	85.08%
2013	Class X	SSC	91.92%

CERTIFICATION

Java Beginner to Master (Udemy)
AWS Cloud Practitioner (Udemy)
Python Data Structures (Coursera)
Agile Software Development (Udemy)

SCHOLASTIC ACHIEVEMENTS

Represented India at International Robocon

1 27th August 2017

▼ Tokyo, Japan

- Stood 6th amongst 19 Asian contries
- Developed a Frisbee Throwing Robot
 - Built a robot with 95% accurancy
 - Used Pressure regulator to vary range and landing position

Academic Excellence Award'20 IIT Kanpur

i 2020-2022

♥ IIT Kanpur, India

POSITIONS OF RESPONSIBILITY

- Teaching Assistant ,IIT K | RCC design & Mechanics of Solid
- Member of Robot Study Circle (Inventory Manager) |
 COE Pune
- Event Head for Robo-wars event | COE Pune

SAURABH SANJAY FASATE

Capgemini | M. Tech, IIT Kanpur

@ saurabhphasate@gmail.com

J 88888 05670

GitHub LinkedIn



ROBOTICS PROJECTS

Developed an autonomous Quadruped Walking Robot

- Each leg has 3 DOF
- · Servo actuators for synchronising walking gaits of robot

Developed an autonomous Shuttlecock Throwing Robot

- Cartesian co-ordinate mechanism.
- 4-wheel Mecanum omni-directional drive for locomotion

Developed an autonomous Frisbee Throwing Robot

- Pneumatic cylinder, linear actuators
- Used Pressure regulator to vary range and landing position

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Investigation and Mitigation of Damage in Suspension-Type Transmission Line Towers Due to Sudden Snapping of a Conductor (M.Tech thesis)

May'21 - June'22

- Non-linear Failure Analysis of transmission line system
- Developing a device to Reduce the Cascading Failure of transmission line.
- Characterized a damping device using Ansys python scripting

Non-linear Analysis Course project (CE622A)

- Study of Pre and Post Buckling behaviour of simply supported beam using Co-rotational Formulation.
- Developed own code in MATLAB.

Stability of Structures

Course project (CE622A)

• Developed a simplified model to simulate response of 3D printed Bi-Stable Mechanisms which we can use as load switch.

Finite Element Method

Course project (CE622A)

• Analysed a beam with a crack using Finite Element Method in MATLAB.